Igor Uchoa

3422 Tulane Dr Apt. 11, 20783

Doctorate student at the Atmospheric and Oceanic Science Department of the University of Maryland. Master of Science in Physical Oceanography at the Oceanographic Institute of University of São Paulo (IO-USP) (2019). Current a Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences Doctorate Student at University of Maryland (UMD). Experienced in Data Analysis (Python/Matlab), with a focus in hydrographic observational data and oceanic model outputs.

Education

Academic Qualifications			
0	PhD Student Atmospheric and Oceanic Science University of Maryland, College Park, Maryland	2021-Present	
0	M.Sc. Physical Oceanography Oceanographic Institute of University of São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil	2017 - 2019	
0	Visiting Undergraduate University of Victoria, Victoria, Canada	2013 - 2014	
0	B.S. Oceanography Federal University of Ceará, Fortaleza, Brazil	2012 - 2016	

Academic Projects

o Master's Thesis - "Eddy-Induced Ekman Pumping in the Vitória-Trindade Region"

Advisor: Prof. Ilson C. A. Silveira (University of São Paulo)

Co-advisor: Prof. Paulo H. R. Calil (Helmholtz-Zentrum Geesthatch)

- Visiting Undergraduate Report: "Colour Remote Sensing on the Strait of Georgia"
 Advisor: Prof. Maycira Costa (University of Victoria)
- Senior Thesis: "Algorithm Development to Estimate Turbidity Dispersion of the Fraser River (Canada) Using the Red Spectral Band of the AQUA/MODIS Satellite

Advisor: Prof. Geraldo Ferreira (Federal University of Ceará) **Co-advisor:** Prof. Maycira Costa (University of Victoria)

Publications

Papers.....

Unraveling the Impacts of Submesoscale Thermal and Current Feedbacks on the Low Level Winds and Oceanic Submesoscale Currents

Year of Publishing: 2024; First author: Lionel Renault

Co-authors: Marcela Contreras, Patrick Marchesiello, Carlos Conejero, Igor Uchoa, Jacob Wenegrat

Journal: Journal of Physical Oceanography

The Air-Sea Interaction (ASI) submesoscale: physics and impact

Year of Publishing: 2023; First author: Louise Nuijens

Co-authors: Jacob Wenegrat, Paco Lopez Dekker, Claudia Pasquero, and collaborators. White-paper from the Lorentz-Center Workshop in Leiden, the Netherlands, Sept 2023

The Brazil Current mesoscale eddies: Altimetry-based characterization and tracking

Year of Publishing: 2023; First author: Igor Uchoa Farias,

Co-authors: Iury Simoes-Sousa, Ilson Silveira.

Journal: Deep Sea Research Part I: Oceanographic Research Papers

Seasonal variability of ichthyoneuston assemblage on the continental shelf and slope of the Southwest Atlantic Ocean, Brazil (20°-23°S)

Year of Publishing: 2019;

First author: Bonecker, Ana C. T.;

Co-authors: Mário Katsuragawa; Márcia Castro; Claudia Namiki; Maria Zani'Teixeira; Igor Uchoa

Farias; Ilson Silveira.

Journal: Journal of Applied Ichthyology

Book Chapter

Water Masses and Oceanic Circulation of the Brazilian Continental Margin and Adjacent Abyssal Plain. Brazilian Marine Biodiversity

Year of Publishing: 2020; Author: Ilson Silveira,

Co-authors: Dante Napolitano, Igor Uchoa Farias.

Springer International Publishing

Academic Experience

0	Graduate Assistant University of Maryland, College Park Advisor: Jacob Wenegrat	College Park, MD Aug 2021 - Present
0	Oceanographic Cruise Coordinator Assistant University of São Paulo Coordinator: Prof. Ilson C. A. Silveira	São Paulo, Brazil 7-21, Dez 2019
0	Teaching Assistant <i>University of São Paulo, Course: Dynamic Oceanography II</i> Coordinator: Prof. Ilson C. A. Silveira	São Paulo, Brazil Jul 2018 – Dez 2018
0	Teaching Assistant - Undergraduate <i>Federal University of Ceará, Course: Physical Oceanography II</i>	Fortaleza, Brazil Jul 2017 – Dez 2017

Federal University of Ceará, Course: Physical Oceanography II

Coordinator: Prof. Ana Paula Krelling

Professional Experience

Teacher Assistant Remote

*Climatematch - Neuromatch Academy*Coordinator: Nick Halper

Jul 2024

Petróleo Brasil (PETROBRAS) / University of São Paulo

São Paulo, Brazil

Position: Oceanographer, Coordinator: Prof. Ilson C. A. Silveira

Jul 2019 - Jul 2020

Main Activities: Oceanographic and Meteorological data processing; Model outputs and reanalysis processing; Plotting and sketch illustration for Data Science; Scientific writing for reports, papers, and presentations.

Wise Up ESL School

Fortaleza/São Paulo, Brazil

Position: ESL Instructor

Jan 2015 - Jul 2017

Main Activities: English Immersion Teaching; Personal and Professional Development Teaching; Test Correction

Extra-curricular Activities

- o 2024-Present Letters for a Pre-scientist (LPS) Volunteer
- o 2024-Present Communications for Science Policy Group University of Maryland, College Park
- o 2023-Present Student Seminar Co-organizer University of Maryland, College Park

Achievements

- 2024 Green Fund Scholarship (Green Fund Endowed Graduate Fellowships in Earth Sciences and Climate Change) - University of Maryland, College Park
- **2024** -Group Achievement Award Submesoscale Ocean Dynamics Experiment (S-MODE) -National Aeronautics and Space Administration
- 2021 College of Computer, Mathematical, and Natural Sciences Deans Fellowship University of Maryland, College Park
- o 2013 Science Without Borders Scholarship Brazil Government.

Talks

Title: Observed air-sea thermal feedback at submesoscale fronts

Invited Talk

American Geophysical Union Annual Meeting, Washington DC

2024

Events

Annual meeting Washington, DC

American Geophysical Union, Invited Talk

2024

Title: Observed air-sea thermal feedback at submesoscale fronts

Ocean Sciences Meeting

New Orleans

American Geophysical Union, Poster

2024

Title: Submesoscale sea surface temperature variability as a sink of eddy energy in a coupled regional model

Atmosphere-ocean coupling at (sub)mesoscales

Leiden, Netherlands

Lorentz Center, Poster

2023

Title: Submesoscale sea surface temperature variability as a sink of eddy energy in a coupled regional model

Physics of the Ocean Summer School

Bad Honnef, Germany

German Physical Society (DPG), Poster

2023

Title: Submesoscale sea surface temperature variability as a sink of eddy energy in a coupled regional model

Mesoscale and Frontal-Scale Air-Sea Interactions Workshop

Denver, CO

US-CLIVAR, Poster

2023

Title: Submesoscale sea surface temperature variability as a sink of eddy energy in a coupled regional model

UMass IMS Research Symposium

New Bedford, MA

University of Massachussetts Dartmouth, Poster/Oral Presentation

2019

Title: Mesoscale Eddies in the Vitória-Trindade Ridge Region: Statistical Characterization from Satellite Altimetry

Workshop Alphas

São Paulo, Brazil

University of São Paulo, Poster

2019

Title: Thinny and Mode-Water Eddies Around the Vitória-Trindade Ridge